# MATT VILLWOCK

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

■ mtvillwock@gmail.com

mtvillwock.herokuapp.com

**(**920) 664-1195

in matthewvillwock

O mtvillwock

## **SUMMARY**

Full stack web developer who strives to produce scalable backend design and intuitive user experience. Strong advocate for well-defined user stories and cross-disciplinary interaction throughout agile product development process.

Background in web development, digital marketing, and public relations. Experience with search engine optimization, content marketing, and informal teaching.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Planet Hopper (May 2015 - present)

- Designed schema with 15+ different models
- Leveraged Hydra gem to make multiple API calls asynchronously to QPX Express API

#### Job Hunt Organizer (April 2015 - present)

- Learned and implemented drag-and-drop functionality in two days
- Achieved deliverable goals using daily standup planning meetings

## Maps with Friends (March 2015 - present)

• Implemented hand-written OAuth login process

#### **Hummingbird (February 2015)**

- Built out server-side API endpoints
- Wrote, delegated, and tracked user stories
- Conducted user trials and implemented design changes based on feedback, resulting in smoother user experience
- (solo) rewrote login process for Heroku deployment after graduation

#### **Stack Overflow Clone (February 2015)**

 Implemented CRUD operations, RESTful routes, asynchronous Javascript calls

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Dev Bootcamp**

## Web Development 2015

Dev Bootcamp is an intensive 19-week program consisting of 1000+hours spent learning Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Object-Oriented JavaScript including AJAX and jQuery, test-driven development (RSPEC), source control (Git), pair programming and agile development.

University of Wisconsin-Madison Bachelor of Arts English and History 2013

University College Dublin International Business 2012

## SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Ruby, Javascript, CSS3, HTML5
WEB FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, jQuery,
SASS, Bootstrap, Rspec

DATABASE TECHNOLOGIES: Postgresql, SQLite
COMMAND LINE TECHNOLOGIES: Git, Unix, Heroku
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT: Agile Development, Kanban Boarding,
Whiteboarding, Programming Language Acquisition
DIGITAL MARKETING: Wordpress, Google Analytics,
Content Management, Keyword Research, Blogging

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## TCI: Teachers' Curriculum Institute

Mountain View, CA

Contract Software Developer · Jun 2015 to Jun 2015

- Built and refactored production code for features that reached 100,000+ users
- Shipped production code 5-6 times/day using continuous integration/deployment

#### Dev Bootcamp

San Francisco, CA

#### Teaching Assistant · Apr 2015 to Jun 2015

- Mentored 30+ students with 1-on-1 code refactoring and programming best practices
- Instructed students in use of 3-4 unfamiliar APIs

## Dev Bootcamp

San Francisco, CA

#### Full Stack Developer Apprentice · Oct 2014 to Feb 2015

 Deployed 4 projects to production in under a week at 4 different times

## **Optimal Digital Marketing**

Appleton, WI

## Creative Content Intern · Apr 2014 to Aug 2014

- Published content marketing blog posts for clients
- Improved client search rankings by researching and implementing high-performing keywords
- Took charge of transferring 50+ clients to new DNS provider

## Leonard & Finco

Green Bay, WI

#### Media Assistant · Oct 2013 to Apr 2014

- Produced compilations of client video and press coverage
- Generated reports of upcoming events for client scheduling use
- Updated 1000+ rows of spreadsheet data, ensuring company accuracy
- Wrote "L&F In the News" summaries for company website